Email: jaggreym@gmail.com Cell: +254 723 073 334

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Nationality: Kenyan Marital Status: Married

Languages: English, Swahili & Kisii (Excellent in both spoken and written)

Spanish & French (Basic)

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Licensed Clinical Dietitian Nutritionist with more than 10 years of experience working in the hospital setting. Diligent in staying updated on latest medical nutrition research and dedicated to using evidence-based nutrition to improve patient care. Expert at nutrition counselling, diet planning and progress monitoring. Thrive in challenging, fast-paced clinical setting and working with various professionals.

### PROFESSIONAL ACCREDITATION

**KNDI** (Kenya Nutritionists & Dieticians Institute)

### **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATONS**

2021- Present	PEOPLES UNI	Masters in Public Health (MPH)
2007 – 2011	UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI	Bachelor of Science Food Science, Nutrition & Dietetics First Class Honors
2006 – 2007	CHRIST THE KING COMPUTER COLLEGE	Diploma in Information Technology  Attained - Distinction
2002 - 2005	KOELEL HIGH SCHOOL	Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education  Attained - B+

#### PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- 2019 Critical Care Nutrition course India Association of Parenteral & Enteral Nutrition (IAPEN)
- 2016 Leadership and Management in health course—University of Washington
- 2016 Principles & Practice of Research & Management & Communication Tools course University of Washington
- 2016 Clinical Management of HIV course University of Washington
- 2016 Principles and Practice of Research and Data Management course University of Washington
- 2014 Health Informatics course University of Washington
- 2011 Management of Severe Childhood Malnutrition.
- 2009 2011 Certificate in HIV/AIDS Peer Education.

P.O. BOX 12317-20100 NAKURU

Email: jaggreym@gmail.com Cell: +254 723 073 334

P.O. BOX 12317-20100 NAKURU

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Feb 2020 – Present KENYATTA NATIONAL HOSPITAL Assistant Chief Nutrition Officer Achievements

- Currently coordinating the review of the KNH Clinical Nutrition & Dietetic Manual.
- Taskforce member in the Ministry of Health Division of Nutrition under the Nutrition Research Technical Working Group
- Actively managing the critically ill patients in the Critical Care Unit.
- Managed to mentor over 40 Nutrition Interns and students annually.

## Sept 2016 – Jan 2020 KENYATTA NATIONAL HOSPITAL Senior Nutrition Officer Achievements

- Actively participated in the review of the KNH Clinical Nutrition & Dietetic Manual.
- Contributed in the development of the 2018 2022 Kenya National Nutrition Action Plan
- Actively participated in the validation of the revised Kenya Clinical Nutrition & Dietetic Manual by the Ministry of Health.
- Actively managing the critically ill patients in the ICU.
- Managed to mentor over 40 Nutrition Interns annually.

### Dec 2012 – Oct 2016 KENYATTA NATIONAL HOSPITAL Nutrition Officer I

### **Achievements**

- Coordinating research activities in the Nutrition department.
- Reinitiated the monthly CME on Enteral & Parenteral Nutrition in the hospital.
- Contributing in creating & publishing Nutrition Guidelines in the hospital.
- Actively managing the critically ill patients in the ICU.
- Participated in various hospital outreaches in giving back to the society.

# Feb 2012 - Sept 2012 GERTRUDE'S CHILDREN'S HOSPITAL Nutritionist/Dietician Volunteer Achievements

- Being an outstanding volunteer in both Gatundu & Kikuyu Medical Camps.
- Actively involved in co-ordinating and implementing SFP project funded by Concern Worldwide in the Gertrude's Children's Hospital Githogoro satellite Clinic.
- Responsible for facilitating various support group trainings.
- Assisted with capacity building on Community Health Programmes through participating in public

## Feb 2010 - June 2011 I CHOOSE LIFE AFRICA Training Group Facilitator Achievements:

 Facilitated and oversaw training of over 130 students on HIV/AIDS Peer Education and Sexual Reproductive Health in 2011.

Email: jaggreym@gmail.com

P.O. BOX 12317-20100 NAKURU Cell: +254 723 073 334

- Successfully managed to supervise a group of 11 trainees on HIV/AIDS Peer Education.
- Organised VCT testing on campus in 2011 that tested over 500 students surpassing the set target.

# 2010 (July - Sept) KENYATTA NATIONAL HOSPITAL Nutritionist/Dietician Intern Achievements:

- Actively participated in planning and supervising the administration of therapeutic feeds in the ICU and Pediatric wards.
- Consecutively provided weekly nutrition education on IYCF, MNCH and PMTCT to more than 25 mothers.
- Acquired excellent report writing skills through ensuring accurate and timely reporting of activities.

## 2009(July - Sept) RIFT VALLEY PROVINCIAL HOSPITAL Nutritionist/Dietician Volunteer Achievements:

- Actively participated in planning and supervising the administration of therapeutic feeds in the ICU and Pediatric wards.
- In-charge of taking anthropometrics, identifying and managing Acute Malnutrition.
- Consecutively provided weekly nutrition education on IYCF, MNCH and PMTCT to more than 25 mothers.

#### **LEADERSHIP**

•	2019 to date	Chair of KNH Clinical Nutrition & Dietetic Manual review Committee
•	2017 - 2019	In-charge of CNE in nutrition department
•	2011	Steered the Upper Kabete Catholic Elders Project Committee.
•	2010 - 2011	Training Group Facilitator with I Choose Life Africa.

### **AWARDS**

	AWARDS		
•	October 2016	Certificate of Facilitation in Burns Symposium	
•	November 2015	Certificate of Merit for presenting scientific paper in Burns Symposium	
•	June 2014	Certificate of Participation in Customer Care Training	
•	March 2014	Certificate of Participation in 10Km First Lady's Half Marathon	
•	Feb 2014	Certificate of Participation in 3rd KNNA Annual Scientific Conference	
•	June 2012	Certificate of Appreciation for being an outstanding Volunteer in Good Hope Medical	
	Camp		
•	Mar 2012	Certificate of Appreciation for being an outstanding Volunteer in Gatundu Medical	
	Camp		
•	Feb 2012	Certificate of Participation in the 3 <sup>rd</sup> National Youth Summit.	

Email: jaggreym@gmail.com Cell: +254 723 073 334

2010 – 2011 Certificate of Participation in Upper Kabete Campus Catholic Community Elders project.
 2008 Certificate of Service from the University of Nairobi for participating in tree planting.

P.O. BOX 12317-20100 NAKURU

### **COMMUNITY WORK**

- March 2012 Actively participated in Gatundu & Kikuyu Medical Camps organized by Gertrude's Children's Hospital.
- December 2010 Participated in the Diabetic screening and Health Education forum organized by Nutritionists without Boarders at Holy Family Basilica Nairobi.

#### SURVEY EXPERIENCE

March 2012 - prevalence of exclusive breastfeeding and associated factors among infants 0-6 months in Kangemi, Nairobi

**September 2011** – The effect of Nutrition education with empowerment in the management of malnutrition in HIV/AIDS.

#### REFEREES

Dr. Steve Gatitu Mrs. Irene Makori Mr. Alexander Mbogo **Deputy HOD Nutrition** I Choose Life Africa Senior Nutrition & Dietetic Officer Department Riverside Drive, No 44 Kenyatta National Hospital Kenyatta National Hospital PO Box 5166-00100, PO Box 20273-00202, PO Box 20273-00202, Nairobi, Kenya Nairobi, Kenya Cell: +254 722 231 001 Cell: +254 723 479 996 Nairobi, Kenya Cell: +254 722 597 605 Email: sgatitu@ichooselife.or.ke Email: mbogoalexander@gmail.com

Email: mogitiirene@yahoo.co.uk